Dang, that thing's the real deal.
This is such a messed up job. Seriously.
Still, I bet I'll breeze through it.
EPISODE 10: REUNION
"To Miss Witch,
Have you been well?
In the time that you've been away,
the air and water in
the town have turned filthy.
My body is in such pain that I can't
go outside, so every day is depressing."
"I dearly wish that you
would visit again soon."
The owner of the bookstore
sent a kind of SOS letter,
so Miss Witch decided to visit the city
for the first time in a while.
You oughta give up on going to town.
The End of All Things showed up near
the border recently and thanks to that,
refugees have been pouring into
the city, so things aren't looking good.
The crow tried to stop her.
Is there some reason why
you still want to go
even if it might mean
facing danger, Miss Witch?
If he sent a letter, it must be serious.
Also, he said he was in pain, so
I want to bring him some medicine.
Miss Witch...
I have to go.
Nah, there's more to it than that, right?
You've never gotten a letter
from a human before now.
You let it go to your head and
now you can't stop yourself.
Emotional abuse.
What? Is that why?!
N-No. Absolutely wrong.
Emotional abuse.
Chomping at the bit after
one pathetic little letter.
What an easy woman!
You know, all you are to that
book guy is a cleaning lady.
Emotional abuse.
I see. You must have always
wanted a pen pal, Miss Witch.
Emotional abuse.
No kidding. That's adorbs! How precious!
But to be honest, I don't want
Miss Witch to go to town, either.
What're all these nasty
mushrooms poppin' up fer?
Ain't that the Champignon Witch there?
The mushrooms she's sprouting are
a lot bigger than normal. I wonder why.
U-Um...
Ahh!
It's talkin'!
Run like heck!
Her breath's s'posed to be poison!
Terrifyin'!
There's probably no
point trying to explain.
But if the villagers are acting like this,
I have a bad feeling about the city.
Careful, Sonny.
If you hold onto the witch like that,
you're gonna get poisoned and die!
C'mon over here.
I'll be fine.
Miss Witch isn't at all dangerous
like the rumors say.
See? I'm the proof of that.
And if you leave the mushrooms be,
they'll wither up on their own.
This should explain everything.
Huh? Oh.
Did my power help Miss Witch?
I was able to protect her,
even though I'm so small!
I'm so glad!
Luna, your right hand and right
foot are moving together.
Then what were those
rumors in town all about,
sayin' that black witches summon
a monster called The End of All Things?
Could be a load of bunk, y'know.
You might be right, y'know.
How would we know, y'know?
What?
Why do I have this strange feeling again?
The End of All Things.
Every time I hear that name,
it wears away my happy feelings
and fills my heart with dread.
Oh. I'm okay.
I gotta keep it together.
I have to protect Miss Witch!
This is... the city?
If you touch The End of All Things,
your skin turns black and rots off
and the air fills with this stench that,
Is that man speaking one of
the refugees from the border
if you breathe it, eats away
at you from the inside.
The land that it poisons
can't be used for a decade.
who escaped The End of All Things?
The heresy and faithlessness
in your heart
is what attracts The End of All Things.
The End of All Things.
The pollution in town is
even worse than we thought.
You gotta be strong and support Luna.
Ain't that her? The witch who grows
all them bad poison mushrooms?
I'm gonna slay her myself!
Hey!
What are you doing?
What if she curses you?!
But that's what the man at
the fountain was saying!
She summons The End of All Things
'cause she's mad about being an outcast.
The black witch is an evil heretic!
Is that true?
My girl ate one of the witch's mushrooms
and suffered for a whole month!
That's wrong!
Begone, you cursed demon!
Please don't!
A hand grew out of the ground!
A dead man's hand!
Boy oh boy, oh boy.
You evil necromancer!
Miss Witch!
Stop it! You don't understand!
Please listen to me!
What now? My charm power
isn't working on them at all.
Not at all!
Luna, let's escape.
There's no point in growing mushrooms
here and Lize is acting kind of strange.
I can't.
Not when the situation is this bad.
If I don't do what I can now...
Oh, moo. You shouldn't be wasting
any of your time on these meanies.
Just leave them be.
Lu—
Oh.
Huh?
Moo?
Why, Miss Witch?
It's too dangerous! Please don't go!
No! I don't like this.
I really don't!
You're gonna grow more? Damn you!
Right in front of me,
Nice shot! Got her!
something terrible is happening
to the person I adore!
And I can't protect her. She protected
me instead. I couldn't even shield her!
Why am I so weak?
Don't you think that's going too far?
The mushrooms are one thing,
but the End of All Things stuff
seems a little far-fetched.
And the air around the mushrooms
always seems like it's clearer.
It sure is refreshing.
Hey! Stop!
She's so far away.
I just remembered something
Luna told me a long time ago.
She was always alone before I came
to live with her, so I asked her,
"Weren't you lonely all the time, Luna?"
And everyone else avoided her.
I said, "Why do you try to purify
the world for people like that?"
"If it was me, I'd hate it so much,
I'd probably curl up and die," I said.
And then Luna said...
I wasn't alone. The forest was
always right there with me.
The forest changes with the seasons,
which is always exciting to see,
and the clouds come to greet
me each and every day.
Sometimes rain and snow do, too.
Even the moon changes shape every day
and follows me wherever I go.
The sun also watches over me
and gives me its blessing.
Quit trying to act so brave, Luna.
None of those are people.
They aren't even animals.
It just makes me feel sad for you.
I-I'm not acting brave though.
Sometimes I almost forget it,
but the truth is I'm not alone,
even if my heart has trouble
recognizing that some days.
Oh.
My body is poisoned and
I am a black witch,
so I will never be able to share
my life with someone else.
But if I decided to live for myself alone,
I think it would start to
make my heart grow numb,
and I would eventually be
swallowed up by loneliness.
So I want to feel connected
and wanted, even if just a little.
However faint it may be, the feeling
that I'm living to help others
is what keeps me alive.
I can't simply abandon someone like this.
But I'm so weak, I'm forcing her
to walk on alone right now.
I want to become stronger!
Strong enough that she never
has to walk alone again.
Lize, settle down. You're gonna
give Hatter an upset tummy.
Strong enough that she doesn't feel she
has to sacrifice herself for others.
That isn't very nice. We can't leave
here until Luna says so, anyway.
I want to protect her.
But crying here now, unable to move,
I feel completely inadequate.
I want to be her shield, strong enough
that she'll keep me by her side always.
Even if it means I lose everything else,
I want to become a magician strong
enough to do that for her.
You, black witch there.
Are you the poison witch growing mushrooms
that are disturbing the peace here?
Huh. It's interesting that such a toxic
witch has slipped through the net
of the black witch hunts that we
white witches have been carrying out.
A white magician?
A vine?
It's so strong!
I have an urgent appointment coming up.
Why don't you take over for me
and toss her into cell block number six?
Yes, Your Excellency.
Just be sure not to touch her, Henri.
It sounds like she's got enough
poison to rot your skin right off.
Understood.
Henri?
Luna.
Well then, you're coming with me.
Do not try to struggle.
If you try to run now, it will
only incite the crowd further
and fuel their suspicions about you.
Henri...
Throw no more stones.
Henri.
You are the Champignon Witch, aren't you?
You should be safe from them now.
Huh?
I am an officer of the crown and
a descendant of the white witches,
but I unfortunately cannot use magic,
so the only one with the magic to untie
that vine is the person who cast it.
But I wonder if your powers as
a black witch are also enough to do so.
Oh... You must be confused.
Of course you are. Sorry.
You'll be all right. The people who are
after you won't come out this far.
You're injured. That must have hurt.
Huh? Oh! What?!
Amazing! The wizard who conjured
that vine is actually very powerful.
Huh. My handkerchief is fine.
So much for the terrible poison witch.
But I don't know, this
is kind of a surprise.
The rumors do mention mysterious powers,
but you're not at all what I imagined.
The instant I laid eyes on you, all I
could think about was protecting you.
And I can still tell you're just a normal,
pretty girl who cries easily.
I guess you can't believe the rumors.
Henri...
Uh-oh. Never mind. We've got to hurry.
You can escape from that exit.
You should be able to get away.
Why would you do this for me?
You're not supposed to
remember me at all.
What if they catch you?
I'll be fine. That supervisor from
before has a terrible memory.
He's already forgotten about
plenty of his prisoners
so I pull this off from time to time.
I can't use magic, but if I play
my inability and connections right,
I can come up with plenty of excuses.
So no need to worry. Just get go—
This is going to sound strange,
but I feel this isn't
the first time we've met.
Maybe we met in a dream or a former life.
Or maybe I'm only being bewitched
by your powerful magic.
Luna, I want you to come with me, to
find what awaits beyond ultimate joy.
The only thing that scares me
is the thought of losing you.
I have a wife and a child.
I don't know why I would even
say that to a girl like you.
Oh... wait. Right.
Black witches don't grow old, do they?
Wait. No, that's beside the point.
Please be do careful,
Cha... um...
Tell me your name. Your name!
Huh? The heck is that? Holy moly!
Wait... something don't feel right.
Guess I gotta deal with that first.
Huh? We're out of the hat.
It looks like there's still
trouble here, though.
I wonder if that means
Luna's magic wore off.
It doesn't look like she's back
yet. I wonder where she is.
I wonder if something happened.
Miss Witch?
Oh! Lize!
No, it's dangerous!
Miss Witch! Miss Witch, where are you?
What?!
Lize!
What is... that?
What just happened?
Are you okay, Lize?
Did any poison get on you?
Yeah, figures.
It already made its way here,
a cursed youngling that was
infected by The End of All Things.
Man, this sucks!
I screwed up wiping out
The End at the border,
and if Flame hears that I sprayed bits
of it everywhere with that tornado,
he's gonna flip out!
And that guy's a nightmare!
Is there any way to keep it from him?
Man, this sucks. What am I gonna do now?
I'm seriously not cut out for
this black magician stuff.
Why are they always
nagging about the method?
As long as it gets done, who cares how?
Man, this makes me wanna quit.
What is this guy's problem?
He does nothing but complain.
He won't stop talking to himself.
But when he showed up,
a strong wind started blowing
Maybe I'll run off. But would I really
get away or would they catch up to me?
and it blew away all of
the lingering blight.
Whatever. Guess I'll see how things go.
And now it feels like that suffocating
feeling inside is being washed away.
And I got the report that Luna
was supposed to be here in town,
so what the heck's that dork doing?
You're a friend of Luna's?
Huh? What's that? Are you
guys friends with Luna, too?
Oh crap! Wow. Don't tell her
what I just said, 'kay?
Wait. Are you one of the Black Magician
Council members? The Wind Magician?
Huh? Whoa. What the... what?
How you know that?
Who're you guys, anyway?
Wait. Eww. Barf!
Huh?!
Must be the wrong guy. He's way too crude.
You got a point there.
A Black Magician... Council?
Huh? Wanna say that again, cow?!
Yikes!
The Wind Magician?
Man, you guys aren't any help at all.
Where is Luna, anyway?
Oh. I already know.
Whoosh!
Huh?!
Wait!
Huh?
Oh...
TRANSLATION: MICHAEL ARNOLD
SUBTITLE TIMING: ANDY ELLIS
EDITING: ELISABETH CRIST
QUALITY CHECK: GABRIELLA ALABANZA
TRANSLATION CHECK: MICHELLE TYMON
NEXT TIME: THE COUNCILOR